10/25/2018 Chuck Chau Resume

Chuck Chau - Walnut, Los Angeles, CA

(626) 233-1319 ★ cchau2@gmail.com ★ https://www.linkedin.com/in/cchau2 ★ https://github.com/volkstrader/resume

Dedicated and versatile software development professional with experience in architecting, planning, coaching, and delivering innovative technology solutions. Demonstrated ability establishing iterative process to set short and long-term IT strategic plan; leading full cycle development to ensure on-time, on-target completion

- Interpreting stakeholders needs into user stories and acceptance criteria
- Giving technical advice to management team
- Hands-on coding architecture framework prototype / solution
- Writing technical documentation and user guides
- Coaching technical staffs on new technologies and processes
- Coordinating internal and external technology resources to realize deliverables

Core Competencies

- AWS Architecture
- Microservices / Docker
- Continuous Integration (CI) Automation Application Lifecycle Management
- Serverless Design and Implementation
- IT Strategic Planning

Technical Proficiencies (5:Fluent, 4:Good, 3:OK, 2:Prior Experience, 1:Experimental)

AWS	CloudFormation, Lambda / SAM, API Gateway, DynamoDb, S3, SNS, SQS, Kinesis, ECS / Fargate, EC2, RDS, Step Functions, CodePipeline, CodeBuild, CodeDeploy
	Go (3) .Net (5) C# (.Net dotnetcore, .Net Standard), Meta-programming, Reflection, Managed Extensibility Framework (MEF), Autofac javascript/TypeScript (4) node.js, RxJs, AngularJS, ReactJS, Data-Driven- Document (D3) UML (4), Python (2), Powershell (3), Bash (1), T-SQL (4), Salesforce-Apex (2)
Platforms	AWS (4), GCP (2), Azure (1), Docker (3), Linux (2), Windows (5), Git (3), Salesforce (3)
Databases	MS SQL Server (4), MySQL (1), DynamoDb (3), Redis (2), ElasticSearch / LogStash / FileBeat (2), Couchbase (1), MongoDb (1), PostgreSQL (1)
Services	SVG, Google DoubleClick for Publisher (DFP), Google Analytic (Universal
Packages	Analytic), Google Tag Manager (GTM), Twilio

Employment History

Principal Software Engineer, Bitcentral, Inc, Newport Beach, CA Software Architect / Senior Software Engineer, ETC Processing Technologies LLC, Los Angeles, CA Senior Software Engineer, CoStar Group, Ontario, CA

1/2018- Present

12/2016- 12/2017

4/2011-12/2016

Previous employments available upon request **Recent Professional Experiences**

Principal Software Engineer

Bitcentral, Inc, Newport Beach, CA

FUEL Video Streaming Engine

Developed HLS streaming engine components in Go, powered by AWS ECS Fargate, DynamoDB, and ElasticCache.

FUEL Media Processing Framework

Taking the initiative to address the ad processing backlog issue, prototyped a highly scalable solution using SNS, SQS and Step Function; to start a new design discussion. Learned from the 10/25/2018 Chuck Chau Resume

prototype, implemented a new processing microservice framework not only comply to business requirement, but also having the goals of highly scalable, efficient, simple and transparent. SpotX Video Ad Integration

Implemented an ad processing pipline integrated with SpotX Video Ad platform to support ad video delivery to HLS streaming engine. The workflow requests VAST from ad platform API, downland the mp4 ad content, convert the video file into Transport Stream - ts files, and then save the ts files to S3.

Local Dev Docker Stack

Created docker-compose scripts to containerize FUEL subsystems, which allow running the FUEL eco-system with developing branch code on local dev box.

FUEL Analytic Schedule Event Generator

Created serverless Lambda application invoked by CloudWatch schedule event. The Lambda applications can be configured to call the Analytic API or send message to queue listened by Analytic processor.

Software Architect / Senior Software Engineer

ETC Processing Technologies LLC, Los Angeles, CA

Client API on AWS API Gateway

Architected a Client API which will allow ETC to pursue new line of security clearing business from online brokers, and integrate their trading platforms with ETC back office; pilot project for exploring AWS cloud platform option

Continuous Integration (CI) Implementation

Defined and applied new Application Lifecycle Management process for development team (dev team), using Team Foundation Server 2017 with Git; targeted to fully automated build and deploy of both application and database changes to different environment

IT Strategic Planning / Roadmap

CEO appointed to lead the effort to create IT Strategic Plan / Roadmap process and policy; documentation templates were created in Confluence, ready for 2018 planning System Architecture Assessment

Documented the current system architecture and proposed a next generation vision, the resulting document was used for FINRA audit and training material for IT onboarding Tooling Assessment / Recommendation

Identified and recommended new tooling software for Team Communication, Project Management, Application Lifecycle Management, and Development; leading to improving IT workflow and accountability

Senior Software Engineer

CoStar Group, Ontario, CA

Enterprise Ecommerce Pricing Engine / Service

Designed and implemented an enterprise solution for calculating shopping cart and generating price sheet, with multi-dimensional pricing model, discount schema, historical and future pricing support; leading to reduction in developer time consumed for pricing update from days to minutes

Marketplace Ad Creative Publishing 2.0

Acted in the role of technical lead to refactor ad creative editing workflow, utilized technologies, such as SVG, D3, Akamai, browser canvas; leading to improve overall performance and artifacts portability

Ecommerce tracking using Google Universal Analytics (UA) with Google Tag Manager (GTM)

10/25/2018 Chuck Chau Resume

Designed and implemented an integrated solution to track ecommerce activities on LoopNet.com website using UA with GTM, enabling ecommerce conversion funnel analytic Marketplace Ad System powered by Google DFP

Designed and implemented an ad platform, integrated with Google DFP, for selling ad spaces on LoopNet.com

Cityfeet.com and Loopnet.com Google Universal Analytic (UA)

Designed and implemented a solution to track user behavior data, such as clicks, social sharing, using Google Universal Analytic (UA)

Recognitions

Nominated CoStar Innovation Award	2014
CoSart Developer Conference	
Winner of CosStar Innovation Challenge	2012
CoStar Developer Conference	

Education

California State Polytechnic University, Pomona 1998 B.S. Computer Science